Dikesh Ray

Mobile: 7827137507

Email: Dikesh.ray@gmail.com

Subject: Cover Letter – Software Developer

Dear Sir/Madam,

I am MCA degree holder having **5.4 years** of experience in analyzing, designing and developing web applications. At present, working with **BLS international Services ltd.** My primary involvement is in developing web and windows application using **C#, ADO.Net, ASP.Net, WCF, MVC, Web Services, JQuery, Ajax, Json, AngularJS, Ms Azure** and **SQL Server** and responsible for complete implementation and testing.

I have extensive experience in C#, ASP.Net, ADO.Net, WCF, MVC, Web Services, JQuery, Ajax, Angular JS, Ms Azure and SQL Server 2008 RD2, 12,14.

Skills:

- Experience in object oriented design and development.
- Having good working knowledge of C#, ASP.Net, ADO.Net, WCF, MVC, Web Services, JQuery with Ajax, Json, Angular JS, Ms Azure etc.
- Experience in relational databases design and development (SQL Server2008 RD2 and 2012, 2014).
- Having good knowledge of HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP v5 JavaScript, JQuery, JSON and Ajax, Angular js 4 & 5, REACT js,
- Experience with **E-commerce site.**
- Good team player and also have ability to work independently in a time sensitive environment.

Please find enclosed copy of my CV for your consideration. Feel free to ask if any further information needed. Thank you for your time, consideration, and forthcoming response. Regards,

Dikesh ray

Dikesh Ray

E-676, street No -10, West vinod nagar, New Delhi(110092)

Mobile: 7827137507

Email: Dikesh.ray@gmail.com

Email: <u>Dikesh.ray@gmail.com</u>

OBJECTIVE

Appetite to learn new things, Team player with Strong analytical and leadership skills, Problem-solving and decision-making skills. A person waiting to take up the challenging assignments and meet the requirements in total and on time.

Work Experience:

- Working with **BLS international Services ltd.** as a **Software Developer** from 05th June 2017 to till date.
- Working with **BRAWN SOFTECH.** as a **Software Developer** from 20th September 2016 to 31th March 2017.
- Working with **HYBEC IT SOLUTIONS LIMITED.** as a **Software Developer** from 01st June 2015 to 31th August 2016.

Trainee Experience:

• Six months **Industrial Training in Microsoft .Net** at **Swarnim InfoSoft Pvt. Ltd.**, Noida (U.P).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Domain	Technologies Used Total 1	Experience (Yrs.)
Language	C#	4.5
Web Technologies	ASP.Net, JavaScript, HTML	4.5
	Web Services, WCF, JQuery, Json and Ajax	4
	AngularJS, MVC, Ms Azure	2
Databases	SQL Server,	4
IDE Tools	Visual Studio	4.5

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- MCA from UPTU with 70%.
- BCA from JAMIA HAMDARD University with 71%, New delhi.
- 10+2 from Bihar intermediate examination council, Patna.
- 10th from Bihar school examination board, Patna.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Awarded as 'Main Anchor' in "E-Kranti-an annual fest" in IME Ghaziabad.
- Organized many Events(**Technical n Cultural Activities**)in E-Kranti in IME Campus
- Organized and participated in National Conference 2012.

Project Details

Project #1: DRA (Drug Regulatory system)

Client : Brawn Laboratories Limited

Environment : Asp.Net with C#, ADO.Net, Web Services, WCF, Java Script,

JQuery and SQL Server 2008 rd2.

Role : Software Developer
Team Size : 6 member per modules.

Project Description: DRA is a DOT NET based web- Application to solve the problem of managing all the Resources of the Drug. It has N-modules (Marketing Management, Regulatory, Production Management) and N-point Login (1.Admin-Login 2.Department login) to Separate the accessibility of the application. Web site http://dra.brawnlabs.com

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Preparing / reviewing the functional requirement document.
- Performing daily coordination with onsite team for client's business requirement.
- Implemented business logic UI, Input Validation.
- Developed the packages, procedures, View, Function used by the application.

Project #2: Chandni chowk restaurant

Environment : Asp.Net with C#, ADO.Net, Web Services, WCF, Java Script,

JQuery, AngularJS And SQL Server 2008.

Role : Software Developer

Team Size : 4 member

Project Description: Chandni chowk restaurant is a DOT NET based web-Application to be provide the facility Online order fast food, dinner, lunch etc. It has fill the three modules (customer Management, User Management, Items Management) and Two-end Login(1.Admin-Login2.User-Login) to Separate the accessibility of the application. http://chandnichowkrestaurant.com

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Performing daily coordination with onsite team for client's business requirement.
- Implemented business logic UI, Input Validation.
- Developed the stored procedures, Synonyms, View, Function used by the application.

Project#3:**OFFIS**(Online,Field,force,Information,System)

Client : Brawn Laboratories Limited

Environment : C#.Net , ADO.Net , Asp.Net , Web Services, Java Script ,

JQuery, Json, Ajax, SQL Server 2008.

Role : Software Developer
Team Size : 6 member per modules.

Project Description: OFFIS provide valuable information on Daily visits to Doctors, Chemists, Stockiest, Stocks of Samples/Gifts with Reps, and many more. After thoroughly analyzing the industry and the way field staff work in the field, we feel the urgent need to develop simple and user-friendly FFA Software, to manage day-to-day reporting process of the field force. Years of experience emerged as an unbeatable product that offers unmatched features, services, enables speedy and hassle-free reporting of field force to their respective reporting heads. OFFIS makes management completely free from the tedious and time taking procedure of manual reporting and paper work and it can be save precious resources in terms of TIME, MONEY and EFFORT, making the process more efficient and transparent.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Preparing / reviewing the functional requirement document.
- Implemented business logic, UI, Input Validation and Database Design.
- Developed the stored procedures used by the application.

Project #4: BLS ECMS

Client : BLS International Service ltd

Environment : Asp.Net with C#, ADO.Net, Java Script, Ajax,

Web Services, SQL Server 2012.

Role : Software Developer
Team Size : 8 member per modules.

Project Description: Smart office is a dot net based web Application to solve the problem of smart office It has five modules (Login Form, Add Employee details, check Employee details, check to the emp leave count and apply to the leave, download Pay Slip, view the time table,)There is many categories through which we can resolve the Employee queries. https://blsinternational.org/hrms/login.html

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Implemented business logic & UI, Input Validation and Database Design with team.
- Developed the stored procedures used by the application.

Project #5: BLS Attestation

Client : BLS International Service ltd

Environment : C#.Net , ADO.Net , Asp.Net , Web Services, Java Script ,

JQuery, Json, Ajax, SQL Server 2008.

Role : Software Developer Team Size : 8 member per modules.

Project Description: The BLS Attestation System is a DOT NET based web-Application to be provide the facility Online Visa passport OCI,PCC and this type of all application to apply online and provide the facility. And resolve the all this type of queries.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Implemented business logic & UI, Input Validation and Database Design with team.
- Developed the stored procedures used by the application.
- Preparing / reviewing the functional requirement document.

PERSONAL DETAILS:-

Father's Name: Kanhaiya ray
Date of Birth: 04-feb-1990
Marital Status: Married
Nationality: Indian

Language : Hindi, English

Strengths : Self-Confidence & Positive Attitude

Hobbies : Software development and Listening to the Adhyatma knowledge

I do hereby declare that all the above information furnished by me are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date:	Dikesh Ray
Date:	Dikesh R